ILGWU Local 23-25 Records 5780/059
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 23-25 Records
1914-2001
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Local 23-25
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780/059
27.67 cubic feet
26.7 linear ft.
Records (documents).
The collection contains minutes of Local 23', minutes of Local 25, and minutes of Local 23-25'. The bulk of the records document the local's activities in the 1970s through the 1990s.
8908245
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
D. Mordente, January 29, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 10, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Locals 23 and 25 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), as well as the local resulting from their merger, local 23-25, also known as the Blouse, Skirt, and Sportswear Workers' Union, were based in New York, New York. Local 23 was chartered in 1903; Local 25 was chartered in 1905. Locals 23 and 25 merged and changed their name to 23-25 officially on November 27, 1963.
Scope and Contents
The first portion of the collection is composed of minutesnot just for Local 23-25, but for its predecessor locals. Early minutes dating back to the 1930s are available for both Local 23 and Local 25. The early minutes are bound and handwritten. Later years include minutes not just for the Executive Board, but also the Membership, Finance, and Grievance Committees, as well as the Health Plans and Skirt and Sportswear Retirement Fund. Meetings for Local 23-25 do not occur until after the merger in 1963. There are also financial documents and ledgers for the Sick Benefit and Health and Welfare Funds and General.
The bulk of the records document the local's activities in the 1970s through the 1990s, and includes files of Edgar Romney (Manager), May Chen (Assistant Director of Local 23-25 Education Program and Assistant Director of the ILGWU Immigration Project), and Susan Cowell (Assistant to the Manager and later, Vice- President). May Chen's files include substantial material on the local's Worker-Family Education Program, and document Chen's organizing with the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance, Coalition of Labor Union Women, and the Asian Labor Committee.
Information on the local can be found in "Local 23-25 Three Year Report," the Report to the General Executive Board (GEB), which provides a synopsis of the locals' yearly activities, Local 23-25 press releases, the digest of newspaper articles from the Chinatown Press, and speeches and remarks by Edgar Romney.
There is additional material on CLUW (Coalition of Labor Union Women) and the members of Local 23-25 that composed the Chinese Committee (see also 5780/095). The local had an active Education Department reflected through the material on English language classes (ESL), sewing classes and citizenship classes aimed at the immigrant members of the local.
Topics with substantial research potential in the collection include the day care center. Members of Local 23-25 worked together to open the Garment Industry Day Care Center in Chinatown for the working mothers of the union. It was the first public-private industrial day care in New York City created through a cooperative effort of Local 23-25 the Greater Blouse, Skirt and Undergarment Association, and the Agency for Child Development of the City of New York.
The collection documents the struggle between the members of Local 23-25 and the contractors in Chinatown. The contractors were unwilling to negotiate a new contract with the union and resulted in 15,000 members of Local 23-25 converging for a rally in Chinatown on June 24, 1982 to garner support for a new contract with chants of "we are one." A second rally held in Columbus Park on July 15, 1982 attracted another 15,000 union members, Chinese garment workers and supporters. The large assembly marched through Chinatown and set up pickets at the unsigned shops and within a few hours, all employers had signed the new agreement. The collection contains information from the local documenting their struggle with the contract negotiations. Items of particular importance include: "Local 23-25 Three Year Report, 1980-1982," newsletters and pamphlets, Local 23-25 Executive Board meeting minutes, and especially press clippings and articles that document the entirety of the dispute from the early contract negotiations to the strike, from a wide range of press sources including Pei Mei News, Sino Daily Express, The United Journal, The World Journal, Women's Wear Daily, New York Post, China Post and China Daily News.
Local 23-25 was very actively involved in immigration matters confronting the immigration members of the union. The Immigration Project was established by ILGWU Local 23-25 on November 19, 1982 to meet the legal challenges confronting the many of its thousands of foreign born members. The project aimed to offer comprehensive immigration legal service at no cost to union members beginning November 22, 1982 and was the first of its kind for a labor union. The Immigration Project counseled members on their rights, processed petitions for adjustment status for permanent residence, provided representation at deportation hearings, processed applications for citizenship, developed and disseminated educational and informational material on immigrant rights. It included all members and retirees of Local 23-25 were eligible, as well as their spouses and dependent children. The project assembled a staff of lawyers, paralegals, social workers, and a multilingual staff that included Spanish and Chinese speakers. They offered English language classes and conducted courses in English and U. S. history and government. In 1987, the Immigration Project was the only union selected as a "Qualified Designated Entity." With the passage of the Immigration Reform and Control Act in 1986, the Immigration Project expanded to meet the needs of the undocumented members of the entire union. At no cost, union members were offered free immigration counseling and legal representation. The staff sought to inform the members and employers of the new law and the services that were now provided. Informational leaflets and local news stories to educated the membership across the country and meetings and radio programs. The collection contains many of the records of the Immigration Project, information on legalization, immigration forms and instructions, citizenship and ESL classes offered by the local, and publicity and press.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/059 P: ILGWU Local 23-25 Photographs 5780/059 PUBS: ILGWU Local 23-25 Publications 5780/095: ILGWU Local 23-25 Records 5780/095 G: ILGWU Local 23-25 Graphics 5780/042: ILGWU Local 25 Publication "L'Operaia" 5780/139 mf: ILGWU Local 25 Publication "L'Operaia" on Microfilm 5780/071: ILGWU Local 25 Publication "The Message"
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Women's clothing industry--New York (State)--New York.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--United States.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; Industrial relations--United States.; Industrial relations--New York (State)--New York.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 23-25 (New York, N.Y.)
8908245
- Minutes, 1938-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Membership Committee and Finance Committee Meetings, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1922-1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes Skirt Makers Union, Local 23, ILGWU, 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes Skirt Makers Union, Local 23, ILGWU, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Executive Board Minutes Skirt Makers Union, Local 23, ILGWU, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minutes of Membership and Grievance Committees, 1932-1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Executive Board and General Membership Meetings of Skirt Makers Union, Local 23, ILGWU, 1947-1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Minutes of Grievance Committee an Appeals Committee Meetings, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Minutes of Finance Committee and Membership Committee Minutes Local 23, 1946-1955 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Skirt and Sportswear Retirement Fund, 1948-1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- General Membership Meetings and Executive Board, Local 23, ILGWU, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes, Local 23, ILGWU, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- General Membership Meetings and Executive Board, Local 23, ILGWU, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Finance and Membership Committees, Local 23, ILGWU, 1955-1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Executive Board and Membership Meetings, Local 23 [folder 1 of 2], 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Executive Board and Membership Meetings, Local 23 [folder 2 of 2], 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Local 23-25 Three-Year Report, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Blouse and Waistmakers Union Executive Board Minutes, Local 25, ILGWU [folder 1 of 3], 1933-1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Blouse and Waistmakers Union Executive Board Minutes, Local 25, ILGWU [folder 2 of 3], 1933-1937 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Blouse and Waistmakers Union Executive Board Minutes, Local 25, ILGWU [folder 3 of 3], 1933-1937 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Blouse and Waistmakers Union Minutes, Local 25, ILGWU [folder 1 of 3], 1938-1948 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Blouse and Waistmakers Union Minutes, Local 25, ILGWU [folder 2 of 3], 1938-1948 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Blouse and Waistmakers Union Minutes, Local 25, ILGWU [folder 3 of 3], 1938-1948 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Blouse and Waistmakers Union Executive Board Minutes, Local 25, ILGWU [folder 1 of 2], 1949-1958 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Blouse and Waistmakers Union Executive Board Minutes, Local 25, ILGWU [folder 2 of 2], 1949-1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Local 25 Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Local 25 Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Local 25 Executive Board Minutes 2 [folder 1 of 2], 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Local 25 Executive Board Minutes 2 [folder 2 of 2], 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Skirt and Sportswear Severance Fund, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Health and Welfare Committee, Local 23, ILGWU, 1955-1961 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Skirt and Sporstwear Retirement Fund [folder 1 of 2], 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Skirt and Sporstwear Retirement Fund [folder 2 of 2], 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- General Membership Meetings and Executive Board, Local 23-25, 1962-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- General Membership Meetings and Executive Board, Local 23-25, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- General Membership Meetings and Executive Board, Local 23-25, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- General Membership Meetings and Executive Board, Local 23-25, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Agreement between National Women's Neckwear and Scarf Association and ILGWU Local 142, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Retirement Fund, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Skirt and Sporstwear Retirement Fund [folder 1 of 2], 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Skirt and Sporstwear Retirement Fund [folder 2 of 2], 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Skirt and Sporstwear Retirement Fund, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Skirt and Sporstwear Retirement Fund [folder 1 of 2], 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Skirt and Sporstwear Retirement Fund [folder 2 of 2], 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Skirt and Sporstwear Retirement Fund [folder 1 of 2], 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Skirt and Sporstwear Retirement Fund [folder 2 of 2], 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Skirt and Sporstwear Severance Fund [folder 1 of 2], 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Skirt and Sporstwear Severance Fund [folder 2 of 2], 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Health and Welfare Fund General Ledger, 1940-1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Health and Welfare Fund Ledger, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Health and Welfare Fund Ledger, 1948-1954 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Health and Welfare Fund Ledger, 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Sick Benefit Fund Ledger, 1939-1946 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- General Ledger, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Local 23-25 Newsletter and Pamphlets, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Settlement between Local 23-25 and Tarzan Sportswear, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Ledger of General Fund, 1915-1933 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Sick Benefit Ledger, 1919-1940 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Membership Committee Meeting Minutes, 1966-1974 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Executive Board Minutes, Local 23-25 ILGWU, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Executive Board meeting Minutes, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- General Membership Meetings Executive Board Local 23-25 ILGWU, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  January
- Health and Welfare Fund Committee Local 23-25 ILGWU, 1983-1986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  January 19 to December 14
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  January 15 to December 16
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes Local 23-25, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  January 14 to December 16
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes Local 23-25, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  January 16 to December 12
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Local 23-25, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  January 11 to September 7
- Executive Board Meetings Minutes Local 23-25 ILGWU, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  General Member Meetings; January 8 to May 16
- General Membership meetings and Executive Board Local 23-25 ILGWU, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  May 21 to December 16
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes Local 23-25, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  September 27 to December 5
- Health and Welfare Fund Committee Local 23-25 ILGWU, 1971-1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  January 26 to October 28
- Committee Meetings Minutes, 1964-1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Civil Rights; Political Education; Chairmen's Meetings; Health Welfare; Campaign Committee
- General Membership Meetings and Executive Board Local 23-25 ILGWU, 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Officers; Executive Board; Delegates Convention; Committees
- Grievance and Appeals Committees Local 23 ILGWU, 1955-1965 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  May 17 to May 5
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes Local 23-25, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Executive Board, 1971-1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  March to October
- Officers and Staff, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Committees, 1953-1962 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Appeals Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Christmas, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Committees (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Convention Delegates, 1956-1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Convention, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Convention, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Convention, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Convention Expenses, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Convention Credentials, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Campaign Committee, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Convention Registration, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Convention Resolutions, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Convention Credentials, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Election Letters Form, 1980-1986 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Elections, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Elections, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Elections, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Election and Objection Committee, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Elections, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Elections, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Election Project, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  Local 23-25
- Elections, 1991-1995 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Health and Welfare Fund Resolution, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Investment (of local's assets) Directions, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Meeting Dates, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Merger of local 91-105 and local 23-25), 1989 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Miscellany, 1970-1994 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  n.2
- New York Joint Board, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Nominations (letters, leaflets, reminders), 1986-1989 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Greater Blouse, Skirt, and Undergarment Association, Morris-Eng Power Struggle (press release), 1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Contract (remarks by Edgar Romney and Wing Fong Chin), 1985 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Contract (remarks by Edgar Romney, press), 1988 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Contract Negotiations, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- (Contract) negotiations, opening speeches, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- (contract Negotiations) Opening Sessions, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Negotiations with New York and Sportswear Associations, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Including remarks by Edgar Romney; Local 23-25
- Agreements, 1991-1994 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Reports to the GEB, 1984-1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Reports to the GEB, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Reports to the GEB, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Reports to the GEB, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Report to the GEB, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Report to the GEB, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  June
- Report to the GEB, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  October
- Report to the GEB, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  February
- Report to the GEB, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  September
- Report to the GEB, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Report to the GEB, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  May
- Report to the GEB, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Report to the GEB, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Report to the GEB, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Report to the GEB, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Report the GEB, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Local 23-25 News, 1987-1995 (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Local 23-25 Shop Rep's Manual Binder (Box 9, Folder 26)
  Binder only; no files
- Local 23-25 Binder (Box 9, Folder 27)
  Binder only; no files; in Chinese
- Chinese CLUW Mailing Lists, 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- CLUW Meetings, 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- New York City CLUW Bylaws, 1980-1986 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- CLUW Meetings, 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- CLUW, 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- CLUW Chinese Committee, 1988-1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Unity House, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  September 16-18
- NYC CLUW Mother's Day Celebration, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  May 21
- Guestbook, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  February 24
- CLUW (Meeting Agendas, Notes), 1990 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- CLUW - Immigration, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- CLUW Certification (of recognition from NYPD), 1990 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  March 6
- CLUW - letter from NYC Major David Dinkins on Occasion of "Working Women Awareness Week", 1991 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- CLUW Mother's Day Dinner Dance Guestbook, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  May 10
- CLUW, 1991-1995 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- CLUW, Asian-Chinese Committee, 10th Anniversary Dinner, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- CLUW, Asian-Chinese Committee, 10th Anniversary Dinner, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Finances, 1984-1988 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Banquet, 1985-1989 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  1 of 2
- Banquet, 1985-1989 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  2 of 2
- Clothing Drive, 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Visit with Chinese Women, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Chinese CLUW Fundraiser, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  February 2
- CLUW Applications for Membership, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- CLUW Members, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- CLUW Account #260365, Local 23-25, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Chinese Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 27)
- CLUW Application Forms, 1984-1988 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  1of 2
- CLUW Application Forms, 1984-1988 (Box 10, Folder 29)
- CLUW News, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- CLUW News, 1984-1994 (Box 10, Folder 31)
- CLUW-IN: Newsletters of the New York City Chapter, 1984-1991 (Box 10, Folder 32)
- Garment Industry Curriculum (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Chancellor's Task Force on Asian-Americans, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Chancellor's Task Force on Asian-Americans, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Chancellor's Task Force on Asian-Americans, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Chancellor's Asian-American Task Force Retreat, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  in Ossining, NY; June 16-17
- Chancellor's Task Force on Asian-American Concerns, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Chancellor's Task Force on Asian-American Concerns, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Parents Coalition for Education of New York City, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Adult Education Week, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  November
- Letter Writing Campaign (to open English language program), 1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Teachers' Resumes, 1986-1986 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- School Permits, 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- School Permits, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- School Permits, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- English Class - Miscellany, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- ILGWU Worker-Family Education Program Staff Manual, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Worker-Family Education Program, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- ILGWU Worker-Family Education Program, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- ESL Material, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Miscellany, 1981-1991 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- ILGWU English Classes, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- English Classes, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Practical English Class, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- English Class (Box 11, Folder 24)
  n.2; Local 23-25
- IGWU English Program "Oral historiesthe Words: A Class Project", 1989 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Student Advisory Committee, 1985-1989 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Graduation, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  June 15
- Graduation, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  June 19
- Graduation, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  June 17
- Graduation, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  June 23
- ESL Graduation, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 31)
- ESL Student Council, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 32)
- ESL Sewing Class, I.S.31, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Immigration Tax Questions, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 34)
- Immigration Press Clippings, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 35)
- Immigration Applications, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 36)
- Immigration, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 37)
- Immigration, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 38)
- Advice Handouts (re Immigration), 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 39)
- Hearing on the Status of Immigrant Children in the NYC Public Schools, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 40)
- U.S. Citizenship, 1987-1992 (Box 11, Folder 41)
- Education Rights (Box 11, Folder 42)
- ESL Certification, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 43)
- Statue of Liberty Essay Contest, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 44)
- Brooklyn ESL Class, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 45)
- ILGWU Worker-Family Education Program; High School of Fashion, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 46)
- Daycare Survey Questions, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 1)